

## **CONTACTS**

+38 098 461 7282



www.chorny-alexander/

in <u>Alexander Chorny</u>

Vinnitsa, Ukraine

## **SKILLS**

- HTML / CSS
  - responsive
  - valid
  - cross-browser
- Bootstrap
- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- React.js
  - Next.js
- Redux
- Figma, Photoshop
- Git

## **LANGUAGES**

- English Upper-Intermediate
- German Intermediate
- Ukrainian Native
- Russian Native

# **ALEXANDER CHORNY**

## WEB DEVELOPER

#### **PROFILE**

I'm a passionate developer with relevant experience in web development. I focus on creating reliable, adaptive, cross-browser web products, emphasizing best practices and accessibility.

In life, I enjoy self-learning, constantly working on improving my technical and communication skills. I strive to learn something new or accomplish something useful every day.

Additionally, I enjoy sports and pursuing diverse personal development opportunities.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Freelance Web Developer Apr 2024 - Jul 2024 (Antalya, TR · Remote)

Participated in a project involving the creation and management of databases. Refined the functionality of a code editor based on CodeMirror, implementing combined language support (SQL and JavaScript) with syntax highlighting and autocompletion. Contributed to various other project features.

Skills Used and Improved: React  $\cdot$  CodeMirror  $\cdot$  TypeScript  $\cdot$  JavaScript  $\cdot$  Lezer  $\cdot$  Recoil  $\cdot$  Git  $\cdot$  Codespaces  $\cdot$  Ant Design.

Freelance Web Developer Jan 2023 - Dec 2023 (Antalya, TR · Remote)

- 1. ONE-OF-PRO (Tech Job Platform) teamwork;
- 2. MYHOBBY-ECOMMERSE (store) I work independently.

Skills Used and Improved: React  $\cdot$  Next.js  $\cdot$  Docker  $\cdot$  TypeScript  $\cdot$  GraphQL  $\cdot$  MongoDB  $\cdot$  Jest  $\cdot$  GitHub/Codespaces  $\cdot$  GitHub/task-board.

Consultant/Content Manager Jul 2009 - Feb 2022 (Vinnytsia, UA) MYHOBBY

Website maintenance, consultations, sales, purchase of goods.

Improvement Of A Website Apr 2015 - Jun 2015 (Berlin, DE - Remote) APPAREL EXPRESS

Improvement of website design and functionality. Refinement of the order sorting module.

Website Development Dec 2014 - Feb 2015 (Kyiv, UA - Remote) KRAINEVA ANASTASIA

Website development for an artist.

#### **EDUCATION**

Data Visualization Nov 2024 - Dec 2024
Front End Development Libraries Aug 2024 - Nov 2024
JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures Nov 2022 - Aug 2024
Responsive Web Design Sep 2022 - Nov 2022
FreeCodeCamp | USA (Remote)

Maintenance of electrical installations Sep 1991 - May 1994 Vocational and Technical Education Center No. 1 | Vinnytsia, UA